Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.13
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Attorney General of the United States, 1988-1991; XIII.
  - News Releases, 2.
    - January 1-15, 1990 (Box 748, Folder 35)
      - AG announced that DOJ employees pledged $1,065,361 for 1990 Combined Federal Campaign, the first time ever to contribute more than a million dollars (Justice Management Division), January 10, 1990; 5.
      - AG announced award of $4.963 million to California for emergency assistance to state and local law enforcement authorities as result of last year's earthquake (Bureau of Justice Assistance), January 12, 1990; 6.
    - January 16-31, 1990 (Box 748, Folder 36)
      - AG announced three-fold increase to $9.8 million in federal anti-drug funds to be provided to North Carolina for state and local drug law enforcement, January 16, 1990; 1.
      - AG opens session of a new Federal Organized Crime Council, January 17, 1990; 2.
      - AG announced telecommunication device for the deaf has been installed in the Office of the AG, January 17, 1990; 3.
      - AG delivered remarks at Bush-Quayle Executive Forum at Constitution Hall, January 18, 1990; 4.
      - AG's statement regarding comments by Dr. Benjamin Hooks, January 22, 1990; 5.
      - AG announced appointment of M. Wayne Huggins, Sheriff of Fairfax County, VA to be director of National Institute of Corrections, January 24, 1990; 6.
      - AG commends Dunne nomination for Civil Rights, January 25, 1990; 7.
      - AG presents Department Awards, January 26, 1990; 8.
      - DOJ announced Scarlet Adams Parham, Community Relations Service Administrative Assistant, receives the AG's Award for Excellence in Administrative Support, January 26, 1990; 9.
      - Statement of AG and Donald Ayer, Deputy Attorney General, concerning the 1991 Budget, January 29, 1990; 10.
    - February 1-6, 1990 (Box 748, Folder 37)
      - AG filed application to investigate allegations of criminal conduct by Samuel R. Pierce, former Secretary of HUD, February 1, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced grants to Indians for child abuse programs (Office for Victims of Crime), February 6, 1990; 2.
    - February 7-15, 1990 (Box 748, Folder 38)
      - AG announced "Big Stick" for Illinois Drug War, February 7, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced that under the direction of President Bush, legislation aimed at strengthening laws to combat employment discrimination is being drafted by the DOJ, February 7, 1990; 2.
      - AG boosted Iowa drug fight with $5.2 million, February 8, 1990; 3.
      - DOJ announced that AG shared drug bounty with Iowa, February 8, 1990; 4.
      - AG announced award of $2.3 million in federal anti-drug funds to Idaho for state and local drug law enforcement (Bureau of Justice Assistance), February 13, 1990; 5.
    - February 16-28, 1990 (Box 748, Folder 39)
      - DOJ announced AG issued an opinion and order granting certain information filed in connection with an application for a joint newspaper operating arrangement (JOA) between Las Vegas' two newspapers remain confidential (Antitrust Division), February 20, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced awarding of $14 million in federal anti-drug funds to Alabama, Alaska, and Arizona for local drug law enforcement (Bureau of Justice Assistance), February 21, 1990; 2.
      - AG approved joint operating agreement for two York, PA newspapers under the Newspaper Preservation Act (Antitrust Division), February 21, 1990; 3.
      - AG calls for longer prison terms, higher fines, and more aggressive forfeiture of illegally gained assets from "white collar" criminals, February 22, 1990; 4.
      - Conference of Mayor's delegation will meet with AG regarding federal anti-drug funding problems, February 26, 1990; 5.
      - AG urges congressional support for campaign reform, February 27, 1990; 6.
      - AG announced Exxon indicted on criminal charges in Valdez Oil Spill, February 27, 1990; 7.
      - AG's statement in response to Supreme Court decision in the Verdugo case, February 28, 1990; 8.
    - March 1-13, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 1)
      - AG's statement concerning the convictions on criminal civil rights charges of five associations of the Confederate Hammerskins, a Skinhead group, in Houston, March 1, 1990; 1.
      - Hal Stratton, AG of New Mexico, announced he will host US and Mexican States' Attorneys General Conference Meeting to be held in Sante Fe (NM, AG), March 1, 1990; 2.
      - AG supports joint production venture Antitrust Bill (Antitrust Division), March 7, 1990; 3.
      - DOJ announced gambling booty re-dealt back to law enforcement, March 9, 1990; 4.
      - AG will address the 1990 Neighborhood Watch Awards Ceremony at the Omni Hotel in Memphis, March 9, 1990; 5.
      - DOJ issued the following statement regarding the US Senate's confirmation of John R Dunne to Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Civil Rights Division, March 9, 1990; 6.
      - AG sent the attached letter regarding the Administration's position on the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) to the following members of Congress, March 12, 1990; 7.
    - March 13-15, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 2)
      - DOJ announced opium warlord Chang Chi-Fu was indicted on 10 federal drug trafficking counts, March 15, 1990; 1.
      - AG and Secretary of the Treasury Nicholas Brady announced an agreement which will add 1,000 US Customs Special Agents to the war on drugs, March 15, 1990; 2.
    - March 16- 25, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 3)
      - AG announced the selection of Terrence Burke to be Acting Administrator of Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), March 22, 1990; 1.
      - AG's statement regarding the unanimous approval by the Swiss Parliament of a new money-laundering law, March 22, 1990; 2.
      - Civil Rights Division submissions to the AG pursuant to Section 5 of the Voting Rights Act, March 22, 1990; 3.
      - AG outlines Federal White-Collar Crime attack, March 23, 1990; 4.
      - AG announces record $395 million for State and Local Anti-Drug Grants, March 25, 1990; 5.
    - March 26-31, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 4)
      - AG will hold a news conference at JFK Federal Building, March 26, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced 3 indictments which charge the entire active leadership and members of the Patriarca Family of La Cosa Nostra with criminal activities, March 26, 1990; 2.
      - Profits from drug dealer assist Prince George's County Police, March 29, 1990; 3.
    - April 1-15, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 5)
      - AG's letter to Honorable Edward M. Kennedy\, Chairman of the U.S. Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources, April 3, 1990; 1.
      - AG shares drug booty with police, April 4, 1990; 2.
      - Savings and loan defendant sentenced to 30 years (Criminal Division), April 5, 1990; 3.
      - AG unveils "Legal Advocates in Education" program, April 10, 1990; 4.
    - April 16-30, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 6)
      - DOJ announced probe of US Bank accounts used by drug lords, April 17, 1990; 1.
      - DOJ announced Dunne to Chair Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (IRCA) Task Force, April 18, 1990; 2.
      - Thornburgh's statement regarding continued cooperation between the U.S. and Mexico, Ixtapa, Mexico, April 19, 1990; 3.
      - DOJ announced statement by David Runkel, Director Office of Public Affairs, regarding continued cooperation between the U.S. and Mexico, April 20, 1990; 4.
      - AG's statement regarding the apprehension of Dr. Humberto Alvarez Machain, April 20, 1990; 5.
      - DOJ announced renaming the Land and Natural Resources Division to "The Environment and Natural Resources Division", April 24, 1990; 6.
      - President George Bush and AG honored 7 people who have made outstanding contributions in assisting victims of crime (Office for Victims of Crime), April 25, 1990; 7.
      - DOJ announced South Carolina law enforcement agencies share seized drug profits, April 30, 1990; 8.
      - David Runkel's Memorandum to DOJ Press concerning treaties governing extradition between the US and Mexico since the last century, April 30, 1990; 9.
    - May 1-5, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 7)
      - DOJ announced enhanced drug abuse treatment program for prisoners, May 1, 1990; 1.
    - May 6-10, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 8)
      - AG and Commerce Secretary Mosbacher unveiled legislation designed to facilitate joint production ventures and help US companies become more competitive in producing new technology, May 7, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced that DOJ proposed amending Civil Rights Act of 1986 to make certain housing discrimination violations punishable as felonies rather than misdemeanors, May 9, 1990; 2.
      - AG, US Attorney Robert L. Brosio, and LA District Attorney Ira Reiner announced that a federal grand jury has returned 2 indictments charging violations of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, May 10, 1990; 3.
    - May 11-15, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 9)
      - Associate US Attorney Freeh to coordinate DOJ's investigation and prosecution into the bombing deaths of Judge Vance and Alderman Robinson and the mailing of other bombs in the South, May 11, 1990; 1.
      - DOJ announced Deputy Attorney General Ayer resigned in order to resume his partnership in the law firm of Jones, Day, Reavis, and Pogue, May 11, 1990; 2.
      - Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights Dunne announced that he found no basis for the federal government to reopen and pursue further prosecution of the events surrounding the MOVE tragedy in Philadelphia, PA, May 14, 1990; 3.
      - DOJ proposes expanded forfeiture law, May 15, 1990; 4.
    - May 16-25, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 10)
      - K. Michael Moore, Director of US Marshals Service, announced appointments to 2 newly-created deputy director positions, as provided in a recent reorganization approved by the AG, May 19, 1990; 1.
      - AG applauds passage of disabilities act, May 22, 1990; 2.
      - AG will inaugurate the DOJ's "Legal Advocates in Education" program, May 23, 1990; 3.
      - AG urged Congress to speed up passage of President Bush's Violent Crime Bill, May 23, 1990; 4.
      - Letter from AG to Senator Christopher S. Bond in response to Bond's question on the current status of the investigation into the Savings and Loans industry, May 25, 1990; 5.
      - AG's letter to the Honorable Arlin M. Adams, May 25, 1990; 6.
    - May 26-31, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 11)
      - DOJ announced indictments of fifteen New York organized crime leaders, May 30, 1990; 1.
      - DOJ announced the indictment of EKOTEK Inc., a Salt Lake City company, and its president, Steven M. Self, in the first federal felony prosecution of environmental crime in Utah, May 30, 1990; 2.
    - June 1-10, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 12)
      - DOJ announced appointment of Joe D. Whitley as the interim US Attorney for the Northern District of Georgia, June 1, 1990; 1.
      - AG approves joint operating arrangement (JOA) for Las Vegas Newspapers, June 1, 1990; 2.
      - AG's statement regarding Federal District Court Judge Kenyon's ruling on redistricting for the Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors, June 4, 1990; 3.
      - Statement regarding passage of joint venture legislation (H.R. 4611) by the House of Representatives, June 6, 1990; 4.
      - AG announced formation of National Drug Intelligence Center, June 7, 1990; 5.
    - June 11-15, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 13)
      - AG's statement on Pan Am 103 investigation in Scotland, June 11, 1990; 1.
      - AG met with the Swedish Minister of Justice Laila Freivalds in Stockholm to express gratitude for cooperation in Pan Am bombing investigation, June 12, 1990; 2.
      - AG commended the Italian government for its passage of a new anti-drug law, June 13, 1990; 3.
      - Dixon indicted on conspiracy charges, June 13, 1990; 4.
      - AG warns Europe on sale of chemicals to cartels, June 14, 1990; 5.
      - AG reviewed with Spanish and Italian counterparts the details of joint efforts to support the government of Columbia and other Andean nations in the battle against drug traffickers, June 15, 1990; 6.
    - June 16-25, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 14)
      - AG and Secretary Brady highlighted the savings and loan prosecutions, June 22, 1990
      - AG and HUD Secretary Kemp announced that USA's and public housing agencies began seizing the leases of drug dealers living in public housing, June 25, 1990; 2.
    - June 26-30, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 15)
      - DOJ announced 40-count Savings and Loans indictment, June 26, 1990; 1.
      - AG distributed more than $5.5 million from the DOJ's Asset Forfeiture Program to 14 Los Angeles area law enforcement agencies for use in the war on drugs in CA, June 27, 1990; 2.
      - AG announced that Edward S.G. Dennis, Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Criminal Division, has resigned effective August 31, 1990, June 28, 1990; 3.
      - AG and Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator Reilly announced the filing of civil suits against 5 different importers of chlorofluorocarbons alleging violations of the Clean Air Act and the EPA's rule to protect the ozone layer, June 29, 1990; 4.
    - July 1-15, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 16)
      - DOJ announced that a federal grand jury in Dallas returned a 17-count criminal indictment against Edwin McBirney III, former owner of Sunbelt Savings Association, July 11, 1990; 1.
      - AG commends the Senate for passing Crime Bill, July 11, 1990; 2.
      - AG commends Congress for passage of Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), July 13, 1990; 3.
    - July 16-25, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 17)
      - AG approved a final rule establishing permanent procedures to be used in adjudicating applications for political asylum in the US, July 18, 1990; 1.
      - DOJ announced that a federal grand jury in New Orleans returned a 3-count racketeering indictment against 31 people for trafficking in the hallucinogen known as "ecstasy", July 19, 1990; 2.
      - AG told the local Law Enforcement Coordinating Committee that during the last two years, 78% of the defendants sentenced in major Savings and Loans fraud cases have gone to prison for terms up to 30 years in length, July 20, 1990; 3.
      - AG sent letter to Senator Howard Metzenbaum correcting Metzenbaum's comments on the "Today" show, July 23, 1990; 4.
    - July 26-31, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 18)
      - AG said that legislation currently in House is more pro-criminal than it is pro-safe streets and called for passage of President Bush's tough, new anti-crime legislation, July 27, 1990; 1.
      - Money laundering is secret accomplice of drug traffickers and guilty verdicts are significant victories in our efforts, July 29, 1990; 2.
    - August 1-8, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 19)
      - AG called for swift action on President Bush's legislative proposal to combat crime in the face of the latest FBI data showing a 5% increase in the violent crime rate in 1989 (Criminal Division), August 5, 1990; 1.
      - AG called on the American Bar Association (ABA) to reverse a series of rule changes which he said could adversely impact upon prosecution of drug traffickers, organized crime and white collar crime criminals, August 6, 1990; 2.
      - AG announced that Jimmy Gurule has been sworn in as Assistant Attorney General for Office of Justice Programs and Dr. Steven Dillingham has been sworn in as Director of Bureau of Justice Statistics, August 6, 1990; 3.
      - AG's statement in connection with the conclusion of the Camarena kidnapping case, August 6, 1990; 4.
      - DOJ announced that Alan Ross Rothery, CA attorney and former chairman of the board of Trinity Valley Savings and Loans Association, was indicted on charges of embezzling over $4 million from the institution (Criminal Division), August 7, 1990; 5.
    - August 9-20, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 20)
      - AG's statement regarding the indictment of Henry Barr in Harrisburg, August 10, 1990; 1.
      - DOJ announced that its Antitrust Division recommended that the AG deny an application for a partial antitrust exemption for a proposed joint newspaper operating arrangement (JOA) between 2 publications in Manteca, CA (Antitrust Division), August 14, 1990; 2.
      - AG's reaction to the ratification of the UN Drug Law Enforcement Convention, August 16, 1990; 3.
      - AG presented USSR Minister of Justice with a copy of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), August 16, 1990; 4.
      - AG distributed $510,345 from DOJ's Asset Forfeiture program to the Chicago Police Department, August 20, 1990; 5.
      - AG calls for passage of President Bush's anti-crime program, August 20, 1990; 6.
      - DOJ and Consumer Product Safety Commission sue to stop import of dangerous toys, August 20, 1990; 7.
    - August 21-31, 1990 (Box 749, Folder 21)
      - AG leaves for Seoul, Korea to represent the US at the Second Conference of Attorneys General of Asia and the Pacific, August 31, 1990; 1.
    - September 1-11, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 1)
      - AG's statement regarding the ABA's rating of Judge Souter, September 4, 1990; 1.
      - AG expressed support for Columbian President Gaviria's plan to fortify his judicial system and free it from the intimidation of narco-terrorists, September 6, 1990; 2.
      - AG announced the initiation of a DOJ Symposium series to be tied into the publication of a Departmental journal to be entitled "Justice", September 10, 1990; 3.
      - AG announced a series of meetings being held with State Attorneys General and District Attorneys to discuss the President's crime package, September 11, 1990; 4.
    - September 12-20, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 2)
      - AG called upon Congress to enact key provisions of President Bush's tough anti-crime bill before the end of the current session, September 12, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced the award of $941,649 to Florida for emergency law enforcement assistance in the Gainesville serial murder investigation (Bureau of Justice Assistance), September 12, 1990; 2.
      - AG's statement on the progress of the Senate confirmation hearing of Judge David Souter, September 14, 1990; 3.
    - September 21-30, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 3)
      - AG warned that state and local law enforcement agencies are in danger of losing hundreds of millions of dollars because of a section of the Crime Bill, September 24, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced that Andrew Gerald McBride has been appointed an Associate Deputy Attorney General in the office of Deputy Attorney General William Barr, September 25, 1990; 2.
      - AG's statement on the nomination of Judge Souter to the Supreme Court, September 27, 1990; 3.
    - October 1-10, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 4)
      - AG announced grant awards of $497,320 to Arkansas and $415,922 to Iowa to improve the quality of criminal history records (Bureau of Justice Statistics), October 1, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced that DOJ will award grants totaling more than $1.7 million to establish offender drug testing programs throughout the criminal justice system (Bureau of Justice Assistance), October 2, 1990; 2.
      - AG announced that DOJ has convicted 131 Savings and Loans executives on major fraud charges in the past 2 years, October 2, 1990; 3.
      - AG will return to the Stuart/Hobson Middle School in Washington, D.C. on behalf of DOJ's Legal Advocates in Education Program, October 3, 1990; 4.
      - AG announced that Dan Eramian will be the new chief spokesman for DOJ and the AG, October 4, 1990; 5.
      - AG's statement on the comprehensive crime control measure, October 5, 1990; 6.
    - October 11-15, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 5)
      - AG released a letter to Senator Bob Dole on the Civil Rights Bill, October 12, 1990; 1.
      - AG recommended that the US Sentencing Commission make amendments to the sentencing guidelines to make the sentences tougher, October 15, 1990; 2.
    - October 16-24, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 6)
      - DOJ announced the filings of civil environmental enforcement cases against 2 steelmakers and a metal manufacturer operating in the vicinity of the Grand Calmut River and Indiana Harbor, October 16, 1990; 1.
      - AG distributed more than $300,000 from the Justice's Asset Forfeiture Program to 10 law enforcement agencies in western Michigan for use in the war on drugs, October 18, 1990; 2.
      - AG announced a 53% decline in the rate of federal prison inmates granted furloughs, October 18, 1990; 3.
      - Attached letter from the National District Attorneys Association calls upon the President to veto any anti-crime legislation that contains the so-called "Racial Justice Act", October 18, 1990; 4.
      - AG announced that DOJ has launched a $2 million program to test innovative neighborhood-oriented policing programs (Bureau of Justice Assistance), October 18, 1990; 5.
      - AG announced that 1989 Young American Medals for Bravery will be awarded (Office of Justice Programs), October 21, 1990; 6.
      - AG released a memorandum to the President stating his views on the Civil Rights Act of 1990, October 22, 1990; 7.
      - AG announced 31 indicted for bank fraud, October 24, 1990; 8.
      - AG and US Marshall announced the completion of "Operation Southern Star," a 10 week drug fugitive manhunt that resulted in the arrests of 3,743 criminals, October 24, 1990; 9.
    - October 25-31, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 7)
      - AG announced a 13-count indictment of 6 members of a Tulsa skinhead group on "hate crime" charges, October 25, 1990; 1.
      - AG announced that Jarrett Woods, Jr. of Dallas, former owner of Western Savings Association, was indicted on fraud charges, October 25, 1990; 2.
      - AG's statement regarding the sentencing of Mayor Barry of Washington, DC, October 26, 1990; 3.
      - AG's statement regarding the death of former AG William French Smith, October 29, 1990; 4.
      - AG announced the creation of the Office on the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) within the Coordination and Review Section of the Civil Rights Division, October 30, 1990; 5.
    - November 1-15, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 8)
      - DOJ announced that the FBI will be reviewing the recent investigations concerning a possible connection between Drug Enforcement Administration undercover activities and the bombing of Pan Am 103, November 1, 1990; 1.
      - AG's statement on voting laws, November 1, 1990; 2.
      - AG praised an international drug enforcement treaty, November 2, 1990; 3.
      - AG announced that DOJ secured a pledge from the North Carolina Republican State Party to not use information from misleading postcards mailed to voters in 29 different counties across the state, November 5, 1990; 4.
      - DOJ announced a sizeable increase in DOJ's budget for investigating and prosecuting Savings and Loans fraud cases, November 6, 1990; 5.
      - AG announced the appointment of a group of senior executives to assist Commissioner McNary in identifying and implementing reforms in Immigration and Naturalization Service, November 6, 1990; 6.
      - AG and EPA announced that during FY 90, DOJ recorded a 33% increase in felony indictments for environmental crimes, November 15, 1990; 7.
      - AG announced that DOJ symposium on civil rights is scheduled for November 16, 1990, November 15, 1990; 8.
      - AG announced that John Edward Logan has been appointed Director of the US Trustee program, November 15, 1990; 9.
    - November 16-30, 1990 (Box 750, Folder 9)
      - DOJ announced that Getty Terminals Corporation was convicted on charges of conspiracy and tax evasion, November 16, 1990; 1.
      - AG and Spanish Minister of Justice Enrique Mugica Herzog signed a Mutual Legal Assistance Treaty (MLAT), November 20, 1990; 2.
      - AG's statement regarding the sentencing of Michael Milken, November 21, 1990; 3.